Guide to the G. Evelyn Hutchinson Papers Relating to Rebecca West
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
G. Evelyn Hutchinson papers relating to Rebecca West
1927-1988
GEN MSS 240
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
7.25
(15 boxes)
The papers document many aspects of Rebecca West's life, including her friendships with the Hutchinsons and others, her marriage and her relationship with her son, Anthony West. In addition to letters from West and her husband Henry Andrews, there are letters from others to Hutchinson about West, including Victoria Glendinning, Alan Maclean, Alexandra Pringle and Diana Stainforth. Writings includes photocopies of early poems by West and a corrected typescript of a group of late poems, "An Old Woman Is Told That She May Have Cancer," as well as writings by Hutchinson on West and on her works. Hutchinson's research files contain material gathered for his bibliography of West's writings, biographical information on her, and files documenting his role as an executor of her literary estate. Clippings consists of articles, book reviews, and other short pieces by and about Rebecca West.
Hutchinson, G. Evelyn (George Evelyn), 1903-1991
West, Rebecca, 1892-1983
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Mr. and Mrs. G. Evelyn Hutchinson from 1959 to 1990.
Conditions Governing Access
Box 15: Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
G. EVELYN HUTCHINSON (1903-1991)
G. Evelyn Hutchinson, a zoologist well-known for his work on the ecology of freshwater lakes, was born in Cambridge, England in 1903 and received his B.A. and M.A. from Cambridge University. In 1928 he joined the faculty of Yale University, rising to become Sterling Professor of Zoology from 1952-71, when he retired from teaching. He became a citizen of the United States in 1941.
Hutchinson, a man of wide literary interests, was introduced to the writings of Rebecca West by his wife Margaret, who admired the British feminist author greatly. Hutchinson himself was taken with her 1928 book of criticism, The Strange Necessity. As he explained in "First Encounter with Rebecca West:"
"The theme of this study is that all important art represents a journey of discovery. She held to this view as a major aspect of aesthetics and from it derived a view that the creative processes of science and art are basically similar. Although the basic idea of the book was hardly noticed by literary authorities, it was a view that instantly appealed to me."
In 1947 Hutchinson began discussing West's Black Lamb and Grey Falcon in his regular American Scientist columns, and sent West copies of these at his wife's suggestion. This led to West's first visit with the Hutchinsons and resulted in a lifelong friendship among West, Hutchinson and his wife. Hutchinson published his bibliography of West's writings, A Preliminary List of the Writings of Rebecca West, 1912-1951, in 1957 to coincide with her appearance at Yale as Terry Lecturer, and was instrumental in her gift of her papers to the university as well.
In addition to his West bibliography and many scholarly articles on aquatic ecosystems and aspects of evolution, Hutchinson's works include The Clear Mirror (1936), A treatise on Limnology (1957, 1967, 1975), The Enchanted Voyage (1962), The Ecological Theater and the Evolutionary Play (1965), and Introduction to Population Ecology (1978). He was elected to the American Academy of Arts and Sciences in 1949 and to the National Academy of Science in the following year. In 1971 he received the Edward Browning Achievement Award, and in 1974 the Tyler and the Cottrell Awards. G. Evelyn Hutchinson died in Cambridge, England in 1991.
Scope and Contents
The G. Evelyn Hutchinson Papers Related to Rebecca West spans the years 1927-1988. The papers are organized in four series: Correspondence, Writings, Subject Files, and Clippings. Box 14 houses Oversize material.
(For the papers donated by Rebecca West to Yale University in 1959, see GEN MSS 195, Rebecca West Papers; for other Rebecca West items, see GEN MSS 239, Rebecca West Collection.)
Series I, Correspondence, is divided into five subseries: Rebecca West, Henry Andrews, Secretarial, Third-Party (Rebecca West), and Third-Party (G. Evelyn Hutchinson). The correspondence between West and Hutchinson, who had long admired West's critical writings, began in earnest in 1947 and continued until West's death in 1983. Hutchinson and his wife Margaret soon became confidantes of West's, and she wrote in much detail about all aspects of her personal life, including her marriage to Henry Andrews, her difficult relations with her son Anthony West and his family, her troubles with servants, and her friendships. Letters written in the 1950s describe her reaction to the publication of her son's novel Heritage and her efforts to block its appearance in Great Britain. She also frequently discussed her political opinions in general and the rise of Senator Joseph McCarthy in particular, noting that her anti-Communist position was often misunderstood as an endorsement of McCarthyism but maintaining that the dangers of that movement were being exaggerated for propaganda purposes.
After Hutchinson expressed his desire to compile a bibliography of her writings, West's letters frequently included current and past newspaper articles and information on her earlier works. The letters also reflect Hutchinson's promotion of West for the Terry Lectures of 1957 at Yale and his involvement in her gift of her papers to that university. West's subsequent decision to open the H. G. Wells correspondence to Gordon N. Ray, and her opinion of his H. G. Wells and Rebecca West, are also the subjects of much discussion.
The letters of West's husband Henry Andrews and of West's secretaries contain news of West during her travels or periods of illness, as well as clippings and information for the Hutchinson's bibliography.
Third-Party Correspondence (Rebecca West) contains miscellaneous letters to and from West, possibly sent to Hutchinson by her for inclusion in her collection at Yale. Third-Party Correspondence (G. Evelyn Hutchinson) holds much West-related correspondence, including letters from her authorized biographer Victoria Glendinning, the publisher Alan MacLean, Virago Press, and Diana Stainforth.
Series II, Writings, is divided into three subseries. Writings of Rebecca West includes galley proof of "Kafka and the Mystery of Bureaucracy," published in The Yale Review in 1957, a corrected typescript of late poems by West, "An Old Woman Is Told That She May Have Cancer," and a typescript of "The Second Person Singular," an unsigned typescript possibly by West. Writings of Hutchinson on Rebecca West contains drafts of his "First Encounter with Rebecca West," the introduction he prepared for a new edition of The Strange Necessity, posthumous tributes to West, and an incomplete essay on West's personality and friendships. The manuscript of Preliminary List of the Writings of Rebecca West is located with associated research material in Series III. The third subseries, Writings of Others, consists of copies of three critical works on West.
Series III, Research Files, is housed in Boxes 6-10 and consists of West-related material gathered by G. Evelyn Hutchinson in the course of his work as her bibliographer and as an executor of her literary estate. There are four subseries. The first, Bibliography, documents Hutchinson's work on A Preliminary List of the Writings of Rebecca West, 1912-1951, and includes research correspondence, drafts of the checklist, and files relating to Hutchinson's planned revision and update of the bibliography. The second subseries, Biographical Files on Rebecca West, contains information on biographies of West, particularly on Gordon N. Ray's H. G. Wells and Rebecca West; documentation of several events in West's life, including the 1957 Terry Lectures at Yale, her honorary degree from New York University, and her funeral and memorial services; and extensive "catalog notes" by Hutchinson on his correspondence with West.
Literary Estate of Rebecca West, the third subseries, includes acknowledgments of West's and Hutchinson's gifts to Yale, lists of unpublished works owned by the estate, and eight folders of notes and minutes of meetings of the literary executors from 1983 to 1985. Subjects include negotiations over the sale of the remainder of the West archive, publication strategies for the still-unpublished work, and the roles of West's authorized biographers.
"Miscellaneous and Unidentified," the fourth subseries, is chronologically arranged and located in folders 242-243.
Series IV, Newspaper and Magazine Clippings, is divided into two subseries: Articles by Rebecca West, and Articles about Rebecca West. The first subseries is further divided into "Articles", "Book Reviews", and "Other Writings." Articles in each section have been arranged alphabetically by title. Most of the pieces date from the post-World War II period, and include commentary on politics, general cultural developments, and the changing status of women in the twentieth century.
The second subseries, Articles about Rebecca West, is divided into "Profiles and Interviews", arranged chronologically; "Reviews of Books by West", arranged alphabetically by title of work; "Reviews of Books about West", arranged alphabetically by the names of the authors of those works; and "Brief Mentions", arranged chronologically.
Oversize contains oversized material from Series II and IV arranged in series order.
Authors, English -- 20th Century; English literature -- 20th Century; Mothers and sons; Women authors; Women journalists; Andrews, Henry; Glendinning, Victoria; Hutchinson, G. Evelyn (George Evelyn), 1903-1991; Maclean, A. D. (Alan Duart); Pringle, Alexandra; Stainforth, Diana; West, Anthony, 1914-1987; West, Rebecca, 1892-1983
- Correspondence, 1927-1988; Series I; 1.6; (4 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  Series I, Correspondence, is organized into five subseries. Rebecca West, Henry Andrews, and Secretarial Correspondence are arranged chronologically. Third-Party Correspondence (Rebecca West) and Third-Party Correspondence (G. Evelyn Hutchinson) are arranged alphabetically by author.
  - REBECCA WEST TO G. EVELYN HUTCHINSON
    - Correspondence, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 7-8)
    - Correspondence, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 12-13)
    - Correspondence, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 17-19)
    - Correspondence, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 23-25)
      With TLS from Henry Andrews to Rebecca West, 1966 Oct 11
    - Correspondence, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 26-27)
    - Correspondence, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 28-30)
    - Correspondence, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 31-32)
    - Correspondence, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 33-34)
    - Correspondence, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 35-36)
    - Correspondence, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 37-38)
    - Correspondence, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 39-41)
    - Correspondence, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 42-44)
    - Correspondence, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 45-47)
    - Correspondence, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 48-50)
    - Correspondence, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 51-53)
    - Correspondence, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 54-55)
    - Correspondence, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - Correspondence, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - Correspondence, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - Correspondence, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - Empty envelopes, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 61-63)
  - HENRY ANDREWS TO G. EVELYN HUTCHINSON
    - Correspondence, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 64)
    - Correspondence, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - Correspondence, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 66)
    - Correspondence, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 67)
    - Correspondence, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 68)
    - Correspondence, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 69)
    - Correspondence, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 70)
    - Correspondence, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 71)
    - Correspondence, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 72)
    - Correspondence, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 73)
    - Correspondence, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 74)
    - Correspondence, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 75)
    - Correspondence, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 76)
    - Correspondence, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 77)
    - Correspondence, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 78)
    - Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 79-80)
    - Empty envelopes, 1953-68 (Box 3, Folder 81-82)
  - SECRETARIAL CORRESPONDENCE TO G. EVELYN HUTCHINSON
    - Correspondence, 1964-69 (Box 3, Folder 83)
    - Correspondence, 1970-79, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - THIRD-PARTY CORRESPONDENCE (REBECCA WEST)
    - Babb, James T., 1958, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 85)
    - Cobb, Edith, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 86)
    - Crook, Arthur
      Related Archival Materials note
      See: Series III, Box 6, folders 228-235
    - MacLeod, Norman ("Bobby"), 1956 Jan (Box 3, Folder 87)
    - [Nichols], Beverley, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 88)
    - Stokes, Sewall, 1927 Nov 23 (Box 3, Folder 89)
    - Wallace, Doreen, 1952, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 90)
    - Yale University, 1955 Feb 10 (Box 3, Folder 91)
  - THIRD-PARTY CORRESPONDENCE (G. EVELYN HUTCHINSON)
    - BC Research, 1983-84 (Box 4, Folder 92)
    - Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library, 1974-88 (Box 4, Folder 93)
    - Bertram Rota, Ltd., 1984 Nov 6 (Box 4, Folder 94)
    - Borgese, Elizabeth Mann, 1964 Aug 6 (Box 4, Folder 95)
    - Braithwaite, Margaret, 1962 Jan 24 (Box 4, Folder 96)
    - British Broadcasting Corporation, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 97)
    - Christie, Kothai
      See: Virago Press, Box 4, folder 144
    - Deakin, Motley, 1982 Aug 16 (Box 4, Folder 98)
    - Edelson, Zelda, 1973 May 10 (Box 4, Folder 99)
    - Faber du Faur, Kurt von, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 100)
    - Gamlens, 1983-86 (Box 4, Folder 101-104)
    - Glendinning, Victoria, 1983-88, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 105-107)
    - Graveley, Will, 1988 Aug 5 (Box 4, Folder 108)
    - Griffin, Martin, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 109)
    - Haight, Gordon S., 1974-80, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 110)
    - Harper's Bazaar, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 111)
    - Harrington, Elizabeth, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 112)
    - Henry W. Wenning Rare Books, 1959 Feb 6 (Box 4, Folder 113)
    - Hunter, Jefferson, 1986 Jun 30 (Box 4, Folder 114)
    - Huxley, Julian, Sir, 1959 Sep 7 (Box 4, Folder 115)
    - Jolly, Alison, 1979 Feb 28 (Box 4, Folder 116)
    - Kenney, Blair, 1969-71, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 117)
    - Kirby, Mr., 1983 Oct 27 (Box 4, Folder 118)
    - Knight, R. T., Mrs., 1959 May (Box 4, Folder 119)
    - Kobler, Turner, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 120)
      With: bibliographical notes on West writings
    - Larison, Lorraine, 1974 Feb 25 (Box 4, Folder 121)
    - Leyshon, Elizabeth, 1978 Jul 11 (Box 4, Folder 122)
    - McBurney, Anne, 1969-88 (Box 4, Folder 123)
    - Macdonald, Sheila, 1982-84 (Box 4, Folder 124)
    - Maclean, Alan, 1983-84 (Box 4, Folder 125-126)
    - Macleod, Norman, 1983-85 (Box 4, Folder 127)
    - Macmillan Ltd.
      See: Alan Maclean, Box 4, folder 125
    - Marcus, Jane, 1978-81, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 127a)
    - Marienthal, ----, 1956 Apr 1 (Box 4, Folder 128)
    - Menaker, Walter, 1971-72 (Box 4, Folder 129)
    - Newsweek, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 130)
    - Olson, Stanley, 1983, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 131)
    - Oved, Yemaiel, 1965-83 (Box 4, Folder 132)
    - Owen, Ursula
    - Pringle, Alexandra
    - Rainer, Dachine, 1967 Mar 17 (Box 4, Folder 133)
    - Ripley, S. Dillon, 1983-84 (Box 4, Folder 134)
    - Scott, Bonnie Kime, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 135)
    - Sports Illustrated, 1983 Sep 27 (Box 4, Folder 136)
    - Stainforth, Diana, 1981-84, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 137-138)
    - Stang, Joanne, 1980 Jan 30 (Box 4, Folder 139)
    - Stevens, Doria, 1959 Feb 11 (Box 4, Folder 140)
    - Stubblefield, R. G.
      See: Gamlens, Box 4 folder 101
    - Time and Tide, 1955 Mar 22 (Box 4, Folder 141)
    - Troxell, Janet Camp, 1966 Oct (Box 4, Folder 142)
    - Urie, Dale Marie, 1987-88 (Box 4, Folder 143)
    - Virago Press, 1981-87, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 144-146)
    - Whitehall, Walter Muir, 1969 Dec 23 (Box 4, Folder 147)
    - Whitney, Helen Cutting, 1987 Feb 10 (Box 4, Folder 148)
    - Williams, David, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 149)
    - Wolfe, Peter, 1967-70 (Box 4, Folder 150)
    - Woman's Journal, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 151)
    - Wright, James, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 152)
    - Yale University, 1955-85, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 153)
    - Yale University Library
      See: Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Box 4 folder 93
    - Yale University President's Office, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 154)
    - Yale University Press, 1976-81 (Box 4, Folder 155)
    - Yale Review, 1986-87 (Box 4, Folder 156)
    - Unidentified, 1972-87, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 157)
- Writings, 1957-83; Series II; 0.4; (1 box)
  Series II, Writings, is arranged in three subseries; Writings of Rebecca West, Writings by Hutchinson on Rebecca West, and Writings of Others.
  - WRITINGS OF REBECCA WEST
    - Early poems of Rebecca West, typescript photocopies, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 158)
    - "Joyce, William", n.d. (Box 5, Folder 159)
      Typescript carbons of article on Joyce for A Concise Encyclopedia of Crime and Criminals
    - "Kafka and the Mystery of Bureaucracy", corrected galley proof, 1957 Jul 25
      See: Oversize, Box 14, folder 319
    - "An Old Woman Is Told That She May Have Cancer", typescript, corrected, [1966?] (Box 5, Folder 160)
      Signed "Conway Power" by West
    - "The Second Person Singular", typescript (Box 5, Folder 161)
      Possibly by West
    - "Verses", typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 162)
    - "A Visit to My Grandmother", typescript (Box 5, Folder 163)
  - WRITINGS OF HUTCHINSON ON REBECCA WEST
    - "First Encounter with Rebecca West", autograph drafts, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 164-165)
    - "Introduction" to The Strange Necessity, autograph manuscript and typescript, [1973?] (Box 5, Folder 166)
    - Labels for a memorial exhibition in honor of West, photocopies, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 167)
    - "On The Return of the Soldier ...a Prefatory Note", 1982, n.d (Box 5, Folder 168)
      Includes research material, autograph manuscript and offprints
    - Preliminary List of the Writings of Rebecca West, 1912-1951
      See: Series III, Box 6, folders 177-83
    - "Tribute to Dame Rebecca West" read at "The Road After 1984" Smithsonian symposium, 1982-83 (Box 5, Folder 169-170)
      Includes autograph manuscript, conference program, speaking contract, and clippings
    - "Tribute" to Rebecca West for the Dictionary of Literary Biography, [1983] (Box 5, Folder 171)
    - Untitled essay on West, autograph manuscript and typescript, incomplete (Box 5, Folder 172)
  - WRITINGS OF OTHERS ON REBECCA WEST
    - Beheim-Schwarzbach, "Rebekka West: 'Der Brunnen fliesst über'", typescript carbon, 1959 Jan 29 (Box 5, Folder 173)
    - Harrington, Elizabeth, "Towards a Sane Feminism: the Early Works of Rebecca West", typescript photocopy, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 174)
    - Wolfer, Verena Elsbeth, "Rebecca West: Kunsttheorie und Romanschaften": Schwiezer Anglistische Arbeiten 66, typescript photocopy, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 175)
- Research Files, 1938-1986; Series III; 1.6; (4 boxes)
  Series II, Research Files, is organized in four subseries. Bibliography is arranged chronologically and by type of material. Biographical Files and Literary Estates are arranged alphabetically by type of material; Miscellaneous and Unidentified papers are chronologically arranged.
  - BIBLIOGRAPHY
    - Preliminary List...1912-1951
      - Research correspondence, 1950-56 (Box 6, Folder 176)
      - Autograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 177-183)
      - Notebook version of the checklist, annotated, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 184)
      - Notebook version of the "Articles" section, annotated, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 185)
    - Research files for proposed revision
      - "Scheme for a More Extended Work" (Box 6, Folder 186)
      - Research correspondence, 1958-83 (Box 6, Folder 187-189)
      - Catalogues, 1977-83 (Box 6, Folder 190-191)
      - "Rebecca West: a Bio-bibliography," by Ida Ruth Patton, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 192)
      - Checklists of uncollected articles compiled by Sheila Macdonald (?), 1984, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 193-194)
      - Miscellaneous notes, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 195-197)
  - BIOGRAPHICAL FILES ON REBECCA WEST
    - Biographies Files
      - Orel, Norman, The Literary Achievement of Rebecca West, 1978-83, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 198)
        Includes photocopies of West's comments
      - Ray, Gordon N., The Literary Achievement of Rebecca West (Box 7, Folder 199-207)
        Includes typescript photocopy, page proof, publication committee comments and minutes, reviews, copies of Chester Kerr's correspondence with Gordon Ray and West's response to Ray
      - West, Anthony, H. G. Wells: Aspects of a Life, 1984, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 208-209)
        Includes excerpts, reviews and interviews
    - West Family Papers
      - Fairfield estate in Dublin: ground rent, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 210)
      - Genealogical charts, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 211)
      - George Square Chronicle: mentions of West, photocopies, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 212)
      - MacLeod, Norman: note on chemistry studies, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 213)
      - Photograph of sketch of West by Violet Trefusis, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 214)
    - New York University Honorary Degree
      - Commencement Bulletin, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 215)
      - Order of Procession, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 216)
    - Notecards on West correspondence
      - Manuscript cards, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 217)
      - Photocopies of cards, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 218)
    - Terry Lectures at Yale
      - Announcement and exhibition notes, 1956-57 (Box 9, Folder 219)
      - Correspondence concerning publication of lectures, 1955-57 (Box 9, Folder 220)
      - Itinerary, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 221)
      - Photographs of West and Henry Andrews at Yale, 1957 (Box 9, Folder 222)
  - LITERARY ESTATE OF REBECCA WEST
    - Acknowledgements of Yale gift, 1954-86 (Box 9, Folder 223-226)
    - Memoranda concerning Yale gift, 1969-83, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 227)
    - Notes and minutes for the literary executors, 1983-85, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 228-235)
    - Lists of unpublished works owned by the estate, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 236-237)
  - OTHER PAPERS
    - Fort Monmouth Security Investigation
      - Final report, typescript carbon, 1954 April 25 (Box 9, Folder 238)
    - Funeral and Memorial Services
      - Obituaries, orders of service, and cassette tape of radio tribute, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 239-240)
    - [Bernard] Levin Interview with Rebecca West
      - Transcript, 1966 Aug (Box 9, Folder 241)
    - Various notes and printed material
      - Manuscript, typescript and printed, 1957-86, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 242-243)
- Clippings, 1922-1987; Series IV; 1.6; (4 boxes)
  Series IV, Clippings, is arranged in two subseries, Works by Rebecca West and Works about Rebecca West, both of which are further arranged alphabetically by type of writing.
  - WORKS BY REBECCA WEST
    - Articles
      - "A" general, 1953-74, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 244-246)
        See also: Oversize, Box 14, folders 320-321
      - "C" general, 1950-61, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 247)
        See also: Oversize, Box 14, folder 322
      - "D" general, 1962-64 (Box 10, Folder 248)
      - "F" general, 1940-61, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 249)
        See also: Box 14, folder 323